

281.851.5004



daniel.huron@outlook.com



danielhuron.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A **creative/art director** with seven years of experience in college marketing and communications. An independent yet team-oriented professional who takes pride in his leadership, project management and creative thinking skills. Dedicated to ensuring projects reach their full creative potential despite any budget or time frame limitations, he strives to create an environment where everyone feels they are part of the solution and the client's needs are always on the top of his team's mind.

Areas of expertise include:

- Leadership
- Project Management
- Creative Thinking

- Design
- Budget
- Event Planning

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

University of Houston: Psychological, Health and Human Sciences Department

Part of the College of Education, the Psychological, Health and Human Sciences department is dedicated to educating tomorrow's leaders by breaking down traditional walls. The programs that make up PHLS share information, share knowledge all with the aim of ending health, education and societal disparities.

Senior Graphic Designer

March 2015 - Present

Project Management: Provided weekly project status reports to department head.

Creative Thinking: Collaborated with PHLS department chair and University of Houston branding to develop department's visual identity guidelines while ensuring those guidelines respected the university's overall brand guidelines.

Design: Produced, shot and edited a video series highlighting our faculty's research efforts. Utilized Adobe After Effects to bring charts to life and help illustrate concepts that might be a bit difficult to understand otherwise. I also produced, shot and edited videos about our department and our programs. Designed program flyers and developed a department brochure.

Houston Community College: Coleman College for Health Sciences

The only institute of it's kind in the Texas Medical Center, HCC Coleman is home to more than 1,000 students, confers degrees and certificates in 20 allied health fields and has strong relationships with institutions such as Texas Children's Hospital, Methodist Hospital and Memorial Hermann.

Communications Coordinator

September 2010 - February 2015

Leadership: Supported graphic designer during production. If she needed copy written, I'd write it. If she needed photographs, I'd go out and take them. I ensured the project was moving along as planned. Collaborated with Public Relations Director to develop plans on how to tackle our communication challenges.

Project Management: Communicated with graphic designer to determine status of projects and what tools were needed to keep it moving forward. Communicated with Public Relations Director weekly to ensure all of his needs were being meet and provide project status updates. Worked closely with third-party vendors to obtain quotes, determine proper artwork submission protocols and coordinate proper, timely delivery of materials.

Creative Thinking: Our department challenged ourselves to deliver high-quality, creative work no matter how little the budget or short the time frame. I challenged our team to find creative ways to deliver our client's message. When we were tasked to promote the launch of a new web service, we created a colorful flip-book instead of brochures that might be easily ignored. We packaged each book in an envelop and included a special USB drive.

Design: Supervised the design of a variety of projects: Coleman Magazine, a college catalog and a variety of posters, flyers, websites and brochures. Oversaw the design of materials for our annual ACE Awards luncheon, ensuring each year's event had it's own unique identity. Collaborated with Seebridge Media in the design and production of a wayfinding monument, which was placed near HCC Coleman's front entrance. In addition to providing directional information, the monument also informed visitors about the college's history and namesake. Developed Keynote presentations for HCC Chancellor.

Event Planning: Managed production of Registered Nursing program's pinning ceremony in May 2014 at Reliant Center. Recruited and managed a group of volunteers, ensuring each person knew their job on the day of the event and helped solve any issues that occurred during the event.

Web Graphic Designer

March 2009 - August 2010

Design: Utilized content management system to update HCC Coleman website. Designed posters, banners, brochures and various other print/digital media to promote our college's programs and other events on campus.

Budget: Printed budget reports for Public Relations Director. Created requisitions and tracked department purchases through PeopleSoft Finance.

Public Relations Assistant

April 2007 - February 2009

Creative Thinking: When I arrived, the Public Relations Director was writing and publishing a two-page Coleman newsletter. I suggested we transform the newsletter into a magazine. We collaborated on a 20-page magazine called Coleman Magazine. I took photos, wrote feature stories, edited copy and designed the magazine.

Design: I designed posters, brochures, flyers and a variety of other materials.

Budget: In addition to design and administrative duties like answering phones, it was my job to print budget reports using PeopleSoft Finance.

Event Planning: One of the first tasks I was assigned was to help plan our first ACE Awards Employee Recognition Luncheon. I collaborated with the Public Relations Director and a third-party vendor to develop the ACE Awards trophy. I developed the nomination forms and helped track them as they were submitted. I served on a committee that planned the luncheon and helped manage the running of the event. Each year I worked at HCC Coleman, I helped plan this event.

EDUCATION

Full Sail University (Winter Park, FL) Master of Fine Arts - Digital Media Design

University of Houston (Houston, TX) Bachelor of Arts - Communications/Print Journalism

OTHER RELEVANT INFORMATION

Software: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, inDesign, Dreamweaver. Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint.

Programing Languages: HTML (moderate), CSS (moderate), Python (beginner)

NCMPR Medallion Awards: Miscellaneous (Gold - 2013), Original Photography (Bronze - 2013), Magazine (Gold - 2012), Promotional video (Silver - 2010), Promotional video (Gold - 2010), Magazine (Bronze - 2010), Promotional video (Silver - 2009), Black and White Photography (Silver - 2009)

NCMPR Paragon Awards: Signage Design (Bronze - 2013), Academic Catalog (Gold - 2012), Magazine (Silver - 2012 and Silver - 2008)